Guide to the New York University Archives Collection of Course Bulletins MC.286
New York University Archives
- NYU Washington, DC (RG 21.39.12), April 2017-ongoing
  - NYU Washington, DC Fall 2017 Courses, April-November 2017
    Course descriptions for classes offered at the NYU Washington, DC campus. Also includes links to courses offered during Fall 2016, Spring 2017, and Spring 2018.
  - NYU Washington, DC Fall 2018 Courses, August 2018-March 2019
    Course descriptions for classes offered at the NYU Washington, DC campus. Also includes links to courses offered during Spring 2019, Fall 2019, and Spring 2020.
  - NYU Washington, DC Spring 2019 Courses, October 2018-February 2019
    Website for the NYU Washington, DC Spring 2019 course listings. Includes courses in business, economics, environmental studies, history, journalism, metropolitan studies, politics, public policy, and global leadership.
  - NYU Washington, DC Fall 2019 Courses, March-October 2019
    This site lists courses that are offered by NYU in Washington, D.C. for Fall 2019 and includes number of credits for each course, brief course descriptions, and sample syllabi for each course.
  - NYU Washington, DC Spring 2020 Courses, March 2019-March 2020
    This site lists courses that are offered by NYU in Washington, D.C. for Spring 2020 and includes number of credits for each course, brief course descriptions, and sample syllabi for each course.
  - NYU Washington, DC Courses, March 2019-June 2020
    This page features course offerings, listed by semester, for NYU DC. There are pages for semesters through Spring of 2021. These pages feature course descriptions from business, economics, environmental studies, Gallatin, history, journalism, metropolitan studies, politics, and public policy departments. The page also links to information about the January and Summer Term programs.
  - NYU Washington, DC Fall 2020 Courses, October 2019-October 2020
    This site lists courses that are offered by NYU in Washington, D.C. for Fall 2020 and includes number of credits for each course, brief course descriptions, and sample syllabi for each course.
  - NYU Washington, DC Spring 2021 Courses, October 2019-August 2020
    This site lists courses that are offered by NYU in Washington, D.C. for Spring 2021 and includes number of credits for each course, brief course descriptions, and sample syllabi for each course.
  - NYU Washington, DC Fall 2021 Courses, October-November 2021
    This site lists courses that are offered by NYU in Washington, D.C. for Fall 2021 and includes number of credits for each course, brief course descriptions, and sample syllabi for each course.
  - NYU Washington, DC Spring 2022 Courses, November 2021-March 2022
    This site lists courses that are offered by NYU in Washington, D.C. for Spring 2022 and includes number of credits for each course, brief course descriptions, and sample syllabi for each course.
  - NYU Washington, DC Summer 2022 Courses, March-June 2022
    This site lists courses that are offered by NYU in Washington, D.C. for Summer 2022 and includes number of credits for each course, brief course descriptions, and sample syllabi for each course.
  - NYU Washington, DC Fall 2022 Courses, March-October 2022
    This site lists courses that are offered by NYU in Washington, D.C. for Fall 2022 and includes number of credits for each course, brief course descriptions, and sample syllabi for each course.
  - NYU Washington, DC Spring 2023 Courses, July 2022-February 2023
    This site lists courses that are offered by NYU in Washington, D.C. for Spring 2023 and includes number of credits for each course, brief course descriptions, and sample syllabi for each course.
  - NYU Washington, DC Summer 2023 Courses, November 2022-June 2023
    This site lists courses that are offered by NYU in Washington, D.C. for Summer 2023 and includes number of credits for each course, brief course descriptions, and sample syllabi for each course.
  - NYU Washington, DC Fall 2023 Courses, October 2023
    This site lists courses that are offered by NYU in Washington, D.C. for Fall 2023 and includes number of credits for each course, brief course descriptions, and sample syllabi for each course.
  - NYU Washington, DC Spring 2024 Courses, February 2024
    This site lists courses that are offered by NYU in Washington, D.C. for Spring 2024 and includes number of credits for each course, brief course descriptions, and sample syllabi for each course.
  - NYU Washington, DC Fall 2024 Courses, October 2024
- NYU Los Angeles (RG 21.39.14), October 2021-ongoing
  - NYU Los Angeles Fall 2021 Courses, October-November 2021
    This site lists courses that are offered by NYU in Los Angeles for Fall 2021 and includes number of credits for each course, brief course descriptions, and sample syllabi for each course.
  - NYU Los Angeles Spring 2022 Courses, November 2021-March 2022
    This site lists courses that are offered by NYU in Los Angeles for Spring 2022 and includes number of credits for each course, brief course descriptions, and sample syllabi for each course.
  - NYU Los Angeles Summer 2022 Courses, March-June 2022
    This site lists courses that are offered by NYU in Los Angeles for Summer 2022 and includes number of credits for each course, brief course descriptions, and sample syllabi for each course.
  - NYU Los Angeles Fall 2022 Courses, March-October 2022
    This site lists courses that are offered by NYU in Los Angeles for Fall 2022 and includes number of credits for each course, brief course descriptions, and sample syllabi for each course.
  - NYU Los Angeles Spring 2023 Courses, July 2022-February 2023
    This site lists courses that are offered by NYU in Los Angeles for Spring 2023 and includes number of credits for each course, brief course descriptions, and sample syllabi for each course.
  - NYU Los Angeles Summer 2023 Courses, November 2022-June 2023
    This site lists courses that are offered by NYU in Los Angeles for Summer 2023 and includes number of credits for each course, brief course descriptions, and sample syllabi for each course.
  - NYU Los Angeles Fall 2023 Courses, October 2023
    This site lists courses that are offered by NYU in Los Angeles for Fall 2023 and includes number of credits for each course, brief course descriptions, and sample syllabi for each course.
  - NYU Los Angeles Spring 2024 Courses, February 2024
    This site lists courses that are offered by NYU in Los Angeles for Spring 2024 and includes number of credits for each course, brief course descriptions, and sample syllabi for each course.
  - NYU Los Angeles Fall 2024 Courses, October 2024
- NYU Tulsa (RG 21.39.15), October 2024-ongoing
  - NYU Tulsa Academics, October 2024
- Liberal Studies Program (RG 21.47), circa 2004-2015, April 2014-ongoing
  - Bulletin, circa 2004-2006, 2007-2009 (Box 55)
    Includes General Studies Program curriculum (circa 2004-2006).
  - Bulletins (PDFs), circa 2004-2006, 2009-2015; cuid17989
  - Liberal Studies (Core Program) Bulletin, April 2014-May 2015
  - Liberal Studies Core Program Curriculum, May 2015- May 2017
    Webpage detailing the course curriculum for first and sophomore years in the Liberal Studies program.
  - Liberal Studies Global Liberal Studies Curriculum, May 2015- May 2017
    Webpage detailing the curriculum for the Global Liberal Studies major, including required first year courses, additional required courses, concentrations, the upper division curriculum, and course offerings for Fall 2016 and Fall 2017.
  - Liberal Studies Bulletin, May 2015-August 2018
    Website containing the online versions for the 2014-2016 and 2016-2018 Liberal Studies Bulletins.
  - Global Liberal Studies Course Descriptions, May 2015-May 2017
    Website containing course descriptions for the Global Writing Seminar, Writing I and II, Cultural Foundations, Social Foundations, Natural Sciences, Sophomore Seminars, Experiential Learning, Senior Seminars, Senior Colloquium and Thesis, Global Cultures, Language Courses, and additional electives.
  - Global Liberal Studies Curriculum, July 2017-ongoing
    Website that details the first year and upper division requirements for Writing, Cultural Foundations, Social Foundations, and Natural Sciences in for the Global Liberal Studies program as well as information on junior year study abroad and senior year thesis work. Also contains links to Google documents containing course descriptions. Cultural Foundations sequence was renamed to Arts and Cultures and Social Foundations sequence was renamed to Global Works and Society in circa 2020.
  - Liberal Studies Writing I and II, July 2017
    Course description for the Writing I and II courses in the Liberal Studies program.
  - Liberal Studies Cultural Foundations, July 2017-June 2019
    Course descriptions for the Cultural Foundations sequence in the Liberal Studies program. Contains sample course titles.
  - Liberal Studies Social Foundations, July 2017-June 2019
    Course descriptions for the Social Foundations sequence in the Liberal Studies program. Contains sample course titles.
  - Liberal Studies Course Program Curriculum, July 2017-June 2020
    Website that details the first year and second year course requirements for Writing, Cultural Foundations, Social Foundations, and Natural Sciences in for the Liberal Studies program. Also contains links to Google documents containing course descriptions. Cultural Foundations sequence was renamed to Arts and Cultures and Social Foundations sequence was renamed to Global Works and Society in circa 2020.
  - Liberal Studies Electives, July 2017-ongoing
    Course descriptions for the electives in the Liberal Studies program. Elective course topics include social sciences, global cultures, and creative writing.
  - Global Liberal Studies Curriculum, July 2017-ongoing
  - Liberal Studies Core Curriculum, March 2019-ongoing
    Webpage detailing the course curriculum for first and sophomore years in the Liberal Studies program. Includes links to Google Documents with course offerings starting in Spring 2019.
  - Liberal Studies Core Curriculum Course Descriptions, March 2019-ongoing
    Course descriptions for Liberal Studies courses in the Writing Sequence, Arts & Cultures Sequence, Global Works and Society Sequence, Global Cultures, Science, GLS Upper Division Courses, GLS Elective Courses, Economics, and Internships.
  - Liberal Studies Undergraduate Bulletin, January 2024-ongoing
    The Liberal Studies bulletin provides an overview of the policies, accreditation, requirements, course offerings, schedules, activities, tuition, fees, and calendar of their undergraduate programs. It also includes the program requirements and a sample plan of study for each major and minor.
- School of Law (RG 22), 1838-1989, May 2014-ongoing
  - Syllabus of Lectures to Be Delivered in the Law School of the University of the City of New York, April-August, 1838; cuid18186 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Law Department of the University of the City of New York, Annual Announcement of Lectures and the Annual Session, 1858-1859; cuid18286 (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Law Department of the University of the City of New York, Announcement of the Annual Session, 1859-1860; cuid18287 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Law School of the University of the City of New York, 1866; cuid18288 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - University of the City of New-York Law School, 1870-1871; cuid18289 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - University of the City of New-York Law School, 1871-1872; cuid18290 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - University of the City of New York Law School, 1872-1873; cuid18291 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - University of the City of New-York Law School, 1873-1874; cuid18292 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - University of the City of New-York Law School, 1874-1875; cuid18293 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - University of the City of New-York Law School, 1878-1879; cuid18294 (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - University of the City of New York, Catalogue of the Law School, 1882-1883; cuid18295 (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - University of the City of New York Law School, 1884-1885; cuid18296 (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - University of the City of New York Law School, 1885-1886; cuid18297 (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - The University Quarterly, excerpts on the University Law School, 1891-1892; cuid18298 (Box 56, Folder 14)
  - University Law School Prospectus, 1894-1895; cuid18299 (Box 56, Folder 15)
  - New York University, University Law School Announcements, 1896-1897; cuid18300 (Box 56, Folder 16)
  - New York University, School of Law, Preliminary Circular, 1897-1898; cuid18301 (Box 56, Folder 17)
  - New York University, School of Law, Preliminary Circular, 1898-1899; cuid18302 (Box 56, Folder 18)
  - New York University, School of Law, Preliminary Circular, 1899-1900; cuid18303 (Box 56, Folder 19)
  - New York University, University Law School, Special Courses in Law, 1900-1901; cuid18304 (Box 56, Folder 20)
  - New York University Bi-Weekly Bulletin, University Law School, June 1901; cuid18305 (Box 56, Folder 21)
  - New York University Bi-Weekly Bulletin, University Law School, May 1902; cuid18306 (Box 56, Folder 22)
  - New York University, University Law School, Preliminary Circular, 1902-1903; cuid18307 (Box 56, Folder 23)
  - Special Announcements, The Law School of New University, 1903; cuid18308 (Box 56, Folder 24)
  - New York University Bi-Weekly Bulletin, University Law School, July 1903; cuid18309 (Box 56, Folder 25)
  - New York University Bi-Weekly Bulletin, University Law School, 1904-1905; cuid18310 (Box 56, Folder 26)
  - Bulletins, 1900-1924 (Volume RG22 Bulletins- Bound 1900-1924)
  - Bulletins, 1924-1938 (Volume RG22 Bulletins- Bound 1924-1938)
  - Bulletins, 1924-1945 (Volume RG22 Bulletins- Bound 1924-1945)
  - Bulletins, 1916-1919, 1928-1944, 1946-1959 (Box 57)
    Includes schedule of lectures (1928-1939).
  - Bulletins, 1938-1948 (Volume RG22 Bulletins- Bound 1938-1948)
  - Bulletins, 1949-1959 (Volume RG22 Bulletins- Bound 1949-1959)
  - Bulletins, 1959-1976 (Box 58)
  - Bulletins, 1976-1981, 1987-1989 (Box 59)
  - School of Law Clinics, May 2014-ongoing
    Year-long and one semester clinics offered at NYU Law. Clinic descriptions include information on course work and fieldwork.
  - School of Law Academic Services, May 2014-September 2016
    This site contains course descriptions, academic policies and other academic resources for students. The School of Law is one of the oldest law schools in the United States. It offers a comprehensive first professional program leading to the degree of Juris Doctor and a graduate curriculum leading to the degrees of Master of Laws, Master of Comparative Jurisprudence, and Doctor of Juridical Science.
  - School of Law Course Descriptions, July 2014-ongoing
    Website containing course descriptions for NYU Law. It contains a listing of required first year courses, course syllabi and assignments, course schedules, course updates, course evaluations, and learning outcomes. Course topics include Administrative Law, Antitrust and Competition Law, Bankruptcy and Creditors' Rights, Civil Procedure, Civil Rights, Clinical Programs, Comparative and Foreign Law, Constitutional Law, Contracts and Commercial Law, Corporate and Securities Law, Corporate Compliance and Enforcement, Criminal Law and Administration, Democracy and Law, Environmental and Energy Law, Evidence, Family Law, First-Year, Health and Benefits Law, Human Rights, Immigration Law, Intellectual Property and Information Law, International Law, International Litigation and Arbitration, Labor and Employment Law, Lawyering and Simulation, Legal Theory and Legal History, Professional Responsibility, Property, Land Use, and Urban Affairs, Security and Law, Stern Business School Preferential, Taxation, Torts and Insurance, Transactional and Law and Business, and Wagner Graduate School Preferential. Access to the course descriptions is easiest accessible from the Schedule of Courses/Course Schedules page.
  - School of Law Schedule of Classes, March 2019-ongoing
    Schedule of Classes at the NYU School of Law. Contains course descriptions, instructor information, course topics, course requirements, and the time and date of each class offered at the New York, Buenos Aires, Shanghai, and Paris campuses. Course listings date back to Fall 2014.
  - School of Law Law Clinics, March 2021-ongoing
  - NYU Law Fall 2022 Schedule of Classes, October 2022
    Website is blank.
  - NYU Law Summer 2023 Schedule of Classes, June 2023
    Schedule of Classes at the NYU School of Law for Summer 2023. Contains course descriptions, instructor information, course topics, course requirements, and the time and date of each class offered at the New York campus.
  - NYU Law Fall 2023 Schedule of Classes, June-October 2023
    Schedule of Classes at the NYU School of Law for Fall 2023. Contains course descriptions, instructor information, course topics, course requirements, and the time and date of each class offered at the New York campus.
  - NYU Law Spring 2024 Schedule of Classes, June 2023-February 2024
  - School of Law Bulletin, January 2024-ongoing
    The School of Law bulletin provides an overview of the policies, accreditation, requirements, course offerings, schedules, activities, tuition, fees, and calendar of their masters, certificate, and JSD/LLM programs. It also includes the program requirements and a sample plan of study for each program.
- Women's Law Class (RG 22.1), 1901-1924
  - Bulletins, 1915-1916 (Box 60)
- School of Law Graduate Division (RG 22.5), 1916-1998
  - Bulletins, 1916-1917, 1941-1942, 1945-1946, 1951-1972 (Box 61)
  - Bulletins, 1981-1998 (Box 62)
- School of Law Juris Doctor Program (RG 22.11), 1981-1993
  - Bulletins, 1981-1993 (Box 63)
- Institute for Law and Society (RG 22.13), 1993-circa 1999
  - Bulletins, 1993-circa 1999 (Box 63)
- School of Medicine (RG 23), 1841-2014; 1841-2014, 2024-ongoing
  - Bulletins, 1841-1881 (Box 64)
  - Bulletins, 1841-1844, 1846-1847, 1855-1856, 1858-1859, 1863-1865, 1870-1898 (Box 65)
  - Medical Department Catalogues, Announcements, and Circulars, 1883-1898; cuid18187 (Box 212, Folder 2)
  - Bulletins, 1898-1910 (Volume RG23 Bulletins - Bound 1898-1910)
  - Bulletins, 1900-1931 (Box 66)
  - Bulletins, 1910-1917 (Volume RG23 Bulletins - Bound 1910-1917)
  - Bulletins, 1920-1930 (Volume RG23 Bulletins - Bound 1920-1930)
  - Bulletins, 1930-1939 (Volume RG23 Bulletins - Bound 1930-1939)
  - Bulletins, 1931-1940 (Box 67)
  - Bulletins, 1940-1950, 1955-1956, 1958-1961 (Box 68)
  - Bulletins, 1948-1958 (Volume RG23 Bulletins - Bound 1948-1958)
  - Bulletins, 1961-1963, 1979-1985 (Box 69)
  - Bulletins, 1985-1993, 1999-2003, 2005-2006, 2008-2010 (Box 70)
  - Bulletin (PDF), 2012-2014; cuid17990
  - Grossman School of Medicine Bulletin, January 2024-ongoing
    The Grossman School of Medicine bulletin provides an overview of the policies, requirements, course offerings, schedules, activities, tuition, fees, and calendar of their masters, certificate, and doctorate programs. It also includes the program requirements and a sample plan of study for each program.
- Post Graduate Medical School (RG 23.2), 1946-1979
  - Bulletins, 1946-1952 (Volume RG23.2 Bulletins - Bound 1946-1952)
  - Bulletins, 1952-1955 (Volume RG23.2 Bulletins - Bound 1952-1955)
  - Bulletins, 1956-1963 (Volume RG23.2 Bulletins - Bound 1956-1963)
  - Bulletins, 1948-1949, 1959-1968 (Box 71)
  - Bulletins, 1968-1974 (Box 72)
  - Bulletins, 1974-1979 (Box 73)
- Bellevue Hospital Medical College (RG 23.6), 1861-1920
  - Bulletins, 1861-1898, 1915, 1919-1920 (Box 74)
- Veterinary College (RG 23.8), 1900-1923
  - Bulletins, 1900-1923 (Box 178)
- Long Island School of Medicine (RG 23.12), January 2024-ongoing
  - NYU Grossman Long Island School of Medicine Bulletin, January 2024-ongoing
    The Grossman Long Island School of Medicine bulletin provides an overview of the policies, requirements, course offerings, schedules, activities, tuition, fees, and calendar of their MD program. It also includes the program requirements and a sample plan of study for the program.
- School of Engineering and Science (RG 24), 1890-1972
  - School of Engineering Bulletins and Circulars, 1890-1900; cuid18188 (Box 212, Folder 4)
  - Bulletins, 1895-1896, 1900-1901, 1913, 1915-1920, 1924-1941, 1943, 1959-1964 (Box 75)
    Includes War Training Courses (1943).
  - Bulletins, 1900-1911 (Volume RG24 Bulletins - Bound 1900-1911)
  - Bulletins, 1912-1925 (Box 188)
  - Programs, 1921-1932 (Volume RG24 Bulletins - Bound Programs 1921-1932)
  - Bulletins, 1925-1932 (Volume RG24 Bulletins - Bound 1925-1932)
  - Programs, 1931-1937 (Volume RG24 Bulletins - Bound Programs 1931-1937)
  - Bulletins, 1931-1937 (Volume RG24 Bulletins - Bound 1931-1937)
  - Bulletins, 1936-1943 (Volume RG24 Bulletins - Bound 1936-1943)
  - Bulletins, 1937-1943 (Box 213)
  - Bulletins, 1943-1951 (Volume RG24 Bulletins - Bound 1943-1951)
  - Bulletins, 1951-1958 (Volume RG24 Bulletins - Bound 1951-1958)
  - Bulletins, 1963-1967 (Volume RG24 Bulletins - Bound 1963-1967)
  - Bulletins, 1967-1972 (Box 76)
  - Bulletins (Evening Division), 1922, 1926-1932, 1935-1941, 1950, 1954, 1961-1962 (Box 77)
  - Bulletins (Graduate Division), 1937-1941, 1959-1964 (Box 78)
  - Bulletins (Graduate Division), 1937-1942 (Volume RG24 Bulletins Grad - Bound 1937-1942)
  - Bulletins (Graduate Division), 1940-1948 (Box RG24 Bulletins Grad - Bound 1940-1948)
  - Bulletins (Graduate Division), 1948-1957 (Box RG24 Bulletins Grad - Bound 1948-1957)
  - Bulletins (Graduate Division), 1957-1963 (Box RG24 Bulletins Grad - Bound 1957-1963)
  - Bulletins (Graduate Division), 1963-1967 (Box RG24 Bulletins Grad - Bound 1963-1967)
  - Bulletins (Graduate Division), 1967-1972 (Box 79)
- College of Dentistry (RG 25), 1865-1984, April 2014-ongoing
  - New York College of Dentistry Announcements, 1865-1988; cuid18191 (Box 202, Folder 2)
  - Announcement, New York College of Dentistry, 1866-1967; cuid18189 (Box 80, Folder 1)
  - Annual Announcement of the New York College of Dentistry, 1867-1868; cuid18311 (Box 80, Folder 2)
  - Annual Announcement of the New York College of Dentistry (Incomplete), 1868-1869; cuid18312 (Box 80, Folder 3)
  - Annual Announcement of the New York College of Dentistry, 1872-1873; cuid18313 (Box 80, Folder 4)
  - New York College of Dentistry, 1873-1874; cuid18314 (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Annual Announcement of the New York College of Dentistry, 1874; cuid18315 (Box 80, Folder 6)
  - Annual Announcement of the New York College of Dentistry, 1875; cuid18316 (Box 80, Folder 7)
  - Annual Announcement of the New York College of Dentistry, 1876; cuid18317 (Box 80, Folder 8)
  - Annual Announcement of the New York College of Dentistry, 1877; cuid18318 (Box 80, Folder 9)
  - New York College of Dentistry Annual Announcement and Catalogue, 1877-1878; cuid18319 (Box 80, Folder 10)
  - New York College of Dentistry Annual Announcement and Catalogue, 1878-1879; cuid18320 (Box 80, Folder 11)
  - New York College of Dentistry Annual Announcement and Catalogue, 1879-1880; cuid18321 (Box 80, Folder 12)
  - New York College of Dentistry Annual Announcement and Catalogue, 1881-1882; cuid18322 (Box 80, Folder 13)
  - New York College of Dentistry Annual Announcement and Catalogue, 1882-1883; cuid18323 (Box 80, Folder 14)
  - New York College of Dentistry Annual Announcement and Catalogue, 1883-1884; cuid18324 (Box 80, Folder 15)
  - New York College of Dentistry Annual Announcement and Catalogue, 1884-1885; cuid18325 (Box 80, Folder 16)
  - New York College of Dentistry Annual Announcement and Catalogue, 1887-1888; cuid18326 (Box 80, Folder 17)
  - New York College of Dentistry Announcements, 1887-1899; cuid18190 (Box 202, Folder 3)
  - New York College of Dentistry Annual Announcement and Catalogue, 1888-1889; cuid18327 (Box 80, Folder 18)